sonicelectronix.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy - Sonic Electronix

## Privacy Policy

We value the trust you place in Sonic Electronix, and we want you to be aware of the safeguards we have in place to respect your privacy. The below policy tells you about the information we gather about you and how we use it. If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policy, please contact us.

**Types of personal information we may gather:**

Sonic Electronix gathers personal information from you in order to provide superior service, communicate offers on merchandise and services which we believe will be of interest to you, customize our communications to you, administer our business, and improve your shopping experience. The following are examples of the personal information we gather from you.

  * **Purchases** \- When you place an order, you give us your name, address, phone number and/or e-mail address plus payment information.
  * **Non-Purchases** \- There may be instances when you are not making a purchase at Sonic Electronix and you give us your name, address, phone number and/or e-mail address, and where applicable, payment information, or when somebody else gives us your name, address, phone number and/or e-mail address, and where applicable, payment information. Some situations when this may occur are when you return or exchange merchandise, receive a gift from Sonic Electronix or enter a contest or participate in a promotion or survey sponsored by Sonic Electronix.
  * **Personal Shopping Account** \- If you create a Personal Shopping Account with us so that you may place orders more conveniently, you authorize us to store your name and shipping address(es), and payment information. If you would like to edit or remove your account information please send us an [e-mail](malito:support@sonicelectronix.com).
  * **E-mail updates** \- When you subscribe to receive Sonic Electronix e-mail updates featuring exclusive offers (like free shipping), product news, special discounts, contest announcements and more, we require your e-mail address. You can unsubscribe at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any promotional e-mail.

**General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Update**

Sonic Electronix collects customer information that you submit to our website in order to operate business. It is secured on our databases and never shared, but it is your right to have more control over this information now. If you would like to inquire about which information you would like to have removed please email gdpr@sonicelectronix.com

**How we use personal information:**

We ask you for certain kinds of personal identifiable information ('Personal data') in order to provide you with the services you request and to process and deliver your order. This is data that you provide to us or that we obtain while you are using our site. Personal Data includes information that can identify you as a specific individual, such as your name, address, phone number, credit card number, email address, age, date of birth, gender, username and password for our site and any other information you may choose to provide either directly or through your use of social media sign-in or features (such as Facebook Connect or Sign in with Google) or as may be required to fulfill the requested service or products. We also may use your personal information to provide you with customized communications and keep you updated on the latest promotions or products that may interest you.

If you purchase services or products as gifts for someone else, you must make sure that you have the right to provide their Personal Data (eg. their shipping information) to us and that those recipients have accepted how Sonic Electronix uses their information as stated in this policy. Personal Data of others is collected only for the purpose of providing such Personal Data to the appropriate shipping couriers or similar third parties (eg. FedEx or USPS) to fulfill the requested service, or as otherwise may be required or permitted by applicable law. 

In addition, our site utilizes 'cookies.' Cookies do not gather any of your personally identifiable information. They do allow us to provide you with a more personalized shopping experience and enable you to fully interact with and complete your transaction on our site. We also collect non-personally identifiable information, including your IP address, search references related to specific searches, location, and similar interactions with our site. When we link non-personally identifiable information with Personal Data, we will treat it as Personal Data under this Privacy Policy.

We may partner with companies to display ads on third-party sites. The partners' applications may use cookies and other code to measure the effectiveness of our ads and to determine the display of ads to you based on your interests both on our site, as well as third party sites you may visit. The information collected is always anonymous, and does not enable any third party to identify you individually. If you prefer not to participate in these services, you can control of this activity by visiting our partner's Opt-Out page by [clicking here](http://www.owneriq.com/opt-out).

**What are cookies?**

'Cookies' are small data files that one of our servers sends to your computer via your Web browser when you connect with our Web site. Their primary function is to help us remember you by tracking your browsing sessions, which enables us to collect non-personally identifiable information (such as your IP address, browser type, and domain name, etc. and provide you with a more relevant shopping experience.

**How we use cookies:**

We use cookies to help process your order through our website and to provide you with a personalized shopping experience. To place an order and complete your transaction on sonicelectronix.com, you must have 'cookies' enabled on your Web browser.

**Cookies also help us:**

  * determine which features and tools you use, and which pages you visit on SonicElectronix.com
  * remember which items you've placed in your shopping cart
  * enable you to check out faster if you've created an account with us

If you have any concerns about leaving cookies on your computer for extended periods, you can delete them using your browser preferences or privacy menus.

**Unique User Log Files**

At times we use IP addresses to generate demographic data or as a fraud prevention measure, otherwise they are not shared, analyzed or distributed.

If you have any concerns about leaving cookies on your computer for extended periods, you can delete them using your browser preferences or privacy menus.

**Our Business Partners**

We may involve third-party companies as a necessary means to fulfill your order. These third parties may be involved with order delivery, e-mail transfer, marketing, and credit processing, among other tasks. Third parties will only be granted restricted access to your personal information for carrying out order related purposes and will not be allowed to use this information for soliciting unrelated services.

**Security**

Our shopping cart and order forms are SSL encrypted to keep your personal and financial data confidential. We keep all of our servers in secure locations. Our database is heavily monitored and safeguarded to prevent misuse from outside operators. We use a firewall and an intrusion detection system among other security measures

We restrict access to all of your information. We have security cameras throughout our premises as well as numerous alarm systems in our building. We only permit departmental and employee access to specific parts of your information, and this access is based on their respective role in fulfilling your order.

**Links to other websites and third party services, including social media**

Our site contains links to other websites or services that are not owned or controlled by us, including links to websites of shipping companies and our advertisers, sponsors, and partners. This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by our site. We have no control over these third party websites, and your use of third party websites and features are subject to privacy policies posted on those websites. We are not responsible or liable for the privacy or business practices of any third party websites linked to our site or third party social media feature or functionality offered on our site, such as Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, and YouTube. Your use of third parties' websites linked to our sites is at your own risk, so we encourage you to read the privacy policies of any linked third party websites when you leave one of our sites, link into our site from another website or through a sign-in feature (for example, Facebook Connect, Sign in with Google, or an Open ID provider), or utilize a third party social media feature or functionality available on our site. 

**Changes to This Policy**

We reserve the right to update our Privacy Policy, so we recommend that you check back as often as it pertains to your concern. If Sonic Electronix elects to use or disclose information in a manner that amounts to a material change of this policy, we will outline the changes here.
